abcsignup.com 2019-03-06

# Privacy Policy, EU-US Privacy Shield, and GDPR - Learning Stream

**Privacy Policy**  
We respect your privacy. This is one reason we have taken the time and space on our website to disclose our information collection practices and our privacy policy. Please take the time to review this document.

Collecting information provides specific benefits to our customers and their website visitors. Information collected is for event registrations only. JTC Technologies does not use registration information for any type of marketing or contact purposes.

  * Information is collected by customers using our software for the following purpose(s):completing or supporting an activity  
building records of individual visitors
  * preserving social history as governed by existing law or policy

**Who has access to the information collected?**  
Learning Stream and its customers — information is used only by organizations hosting events using learningstream.com.

**Delivery services possibly not sharing our privacy policy**  
Of the information we do collect, we allow our visitors the following access to the information:

**Access is given to all collected information**  
If you believe that our website has collected incorrect information or if you would like to dispute any information, please contact us using the information below.

This privacy statement applies to the website of:  
JTC Technologies, LLC  
1941 Bishop Lane, Suite 400  
Louisville KY 40218 US  
502-454-2850  
jtctech@jtctech.com

**EU-US Privacy Shield Policy**  
Learningstream.com is owned and operated by JTC Technologies, LLC. JTC Technologies, LLC complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. JTC Technologies, LLC has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/

JTC Technologies, LLC, (the “Company”) provides software to organizations that collect registrant data via online forms. This may include contact information such as name, email address, phone numbers, and mailing address. Protecting consumer privacy is important to the Company. This privacy policy outlines our general policy and practices for implementing the Principles, including the types of information we gather, how we use it and the notice and choice affected individuals have regarding our use of and their ability to correct that information. This privacy policy applies to all personal information received by the Company whether in electronic, paper or verbal format. This may include data shared with third parties at the specific request of the Company’s customers via application interfaces for transaction processing.

Definitions  
“Personal Information” or “Information” means information that (1) is transferred from the EU to the United States; (2) is recorded in any form; (3) is about, or pertains to a specific individual; and (4) can be linked to that individual.  
“Sensitive Personal Information” means personal information that reveals race, ethnic origin, sexual orientation, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership or that concerns an individual’s health.  
Individuals whose data the Company handles have the right at any time to correct or delete it. The Company provides the means for individuals to access their account to remove, add, or revise data.

Principles  
Notice The Company shall inform an individual of the purpose for which it collects and uses the Personal Information and the types of non-agent third parties to which the Company discloses or may disclose that Information. Company shall provide the individual with the choice and means for limiting the use and disclosure of their Personal Information. Notice will be provided in clear and conspicuous language when individuals are first asked to provide Personal Information to the Company, or as soon as practicable thereafter, and in any event before the Company uses or discloses the Information for a purpose other than for which it was originally collected.

Choice  
The Company does not disclose third-party information. However, individuals have the right to choose (opt out) whether their Personal Information is (1) to be disclosed to a third party or (2) to be used for a purpose other than the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. For Sensitive Personal Information, the Company will give individuals the opportunity to affirmatively or explicitly (opt out) consent to the disclosure of the information for a purpose other than the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. Company shall treat Sensitive Personal Information received from an individual the same as the individual would treat and identify it as Sensitive Personal Information. Opt-out links will be available on many forms. Individuals may also send requests to support@learningstream.com.

Onward Transfers  
Prior to disclosing Personal Information to a third party, Company shall notify the individual of such disclosure and allow the individual the choice (opt out) of such disclosure. Company shall ensure that any third party for which Personal Information may be disclosed subscribes to the Principles or are subject to law providing the same level of privacy protection as is required by the Principles and agree in writing to provide an adequate level of privacy protection. The Company does not disclose information to third parties.

Please note that Company is obliged to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

In cases of onward transfer of Privacy Shield data to third parties, Company is potentially liable.

Data Security  
Company shall take reasonable steps to protect the Information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. Company has put in place appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the Information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration or destruction. Company cannot guarantee the security of Information on or transmitted via the Internet.

Data Integrity  
Company shall only process Personal Information in a way that is compatible with and relevant for the purpose for which it was collected or authorized by the individual. To the extent necessary for those purposes, Company shall take reasonable steps to ensure that Personal Information is accurate, complete, current and reliable for its intended use.

Access  
Company acknowledges the right of EU individuals to access their personal data. Company shall allow an individual access to their Personal Information and allow the individual to correct, amend or delete inaccurate information, except where the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to the privacy of the individual in the case in question or where the rights of persons other than the individual would be violated. The company provides links to allow individuals to revise Personal Information. Individuals may also contact the Company via support@learningstream.com.

Enforcement  
Company uses a self-assessment approach to assure compliance with this privacy policy and periodically verifies that the policy is accurate, comprehensive for the information intended to be covered, prominently displayed, completely implemented and accessible and in conformity with the Principles. We encourage interested persons to raise any concerns using the contact information provided below and we will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of Personal Information in accordance with the Principles.  
If a complaint or dispute cannot be resolved through our internal process, we agree to dispute resolution using (an independent resource mechanism) as a third party resolution provider.

Amendments  
This privacy policy may be amended from time to time consistent with the requirements of the Privacy Shield. We will post any revised policy on this website.

Information Subject to Other Policies  
The Company is committed to following the Principles for all Personal Information within the scope of the Privacy Shield Frameworks. However, certain information is subject to policies of the Company that may differ in some respects from the general policies set forth in this privacy policy.

In compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles, JTC Technologies, LLC commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact JTC Technologies, LLC at:

Attention: Todd Chandler  
JTC Technologies, LLC  
1941 Bishop Lane, Suite 400  
Louisville, KY 40218  
502-454-2850

JTC Technologies, LLC is further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/ for more information and to file a complaint.

If your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, and your inquiry or complaint involves human resources data transferred from the EU in the context of the employment relationship, you may have your complaint considered by an independent recourse mechanism: for EU/EEA Data Subjects, a panel established by the EU data protection authorities (“DPA Panel”). To do so, you should contact the state or national data protection or labor authority in the jurisdiction where you work. JTC Technologies, LLC agrees to cooperate with the relevant national DPAs and to comply with the decisions of the DPA Panel.

Finally, and under certain limited conditions, EU individuals may invoke binding arbitration as a last resort before the Privacy Shield Panel.

The Company is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission.  
Effective August 29, 2016

**EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)**

The data controller responsible for your personal information for purposes of the applicable European Union data protection law is:  
JTC Technologies, LLC dba Learning Stream  
1941 Bishop Lane, Suite 400  
Louisville, Kentucky, USA 40218  
+1 502 454 2851

If you have any questions or concerns about our use of your personal data, you may contact us at the address above. Or you may use **[this form](https://reg.abcsignup.com/s_reg/reg_registration_maintenance.aspx?ek=0003-0003-4F6F0F511A414C378F45F3D5207E70AC)** to request the removal of your personal data from our system. Please allow no more than 30 days for removal of data to occur.

**How we use your data**  
Learning Stream’s customers use the software to collect information from registrants for purposes of training, classes, meetings, and other events. We process this information as part of binding agreements with our customers who then offer their services to their customers (employees, customers, or to the general public). Their customers request access to those services via online forms.  
As part of the registration process, Learning Stream customers will send messages such as confirmation, wait list, and reminder emails. You may opt out of these messages.

**No data sharing**  
Learning Stream does not sell or share personal information collected via its online forms. Only customers that request such information via online forms can access it.

**Third-country transfer**  
If you are within the EU and you complete a Learning Stream form, you are transferring data to a third country (U.S.A.). The European Commission has determined the U.S.A. provides an “adequate level of data protection.” This assumes the company is within the Privacy Shield Framework, which Learning Stream is.

**How long we retain your data**  
When a customer no longer uses Learning Stream for data collection, Learning Stream purges all data associated with that account. The customer also has the means to purge data while the account remains active.  
• Your rights as the data provider  
You have the right to know what Learning Stream does with your data. This privacy policy outlines that.  
• You have the right to access your data at any time.  
• You may request removal of your data at any time. To do so, you may contact the Learning Stream customer that uses our system to collect your data. You may also contact Learning Stream directly using **[this form](https://reg.abcsignup.com/s_reg/reg_registration_maintenance.aspx?ek=0003-0003-4F6F0F511A414C378F45F3D5207E70AC)** or by writing us using the address listed above.  
• You may also file a complaint any time directly with Learning Stream using **[this form](https://reg.abcsignup.com/s_reg/reg_registration_maintenance.aspx?ek=0003-0003-4F6F0F511A414C378F45F3D5207E70AC)** or the above address.  
• You have the right to rectify any personal information you believe is incorrect.

**Withdrawing your consent**  
Should you withdraw your consent, which was previously given, you may do so at any time. Any information collected prior to your withdrawing consent would still be considered lawful. You should also contact the Learning Stream customer which collected your data via online forms.
